EMIL DRAGAN

email: emil-mircea@protonmail.com
mobile: 0034 615 248
address: Carrer de Lepant, 339, Barcelona, Spain

PROFILE

A full stack developer with 4 years of experience. I estimate spending 40% of the time developing backend APIs with Rails and 60% of the time building UI's with React. Experience in business analysis helps me find profitable software solutions.

SKILLS

- *LANGUAGES: RUBY, JAVASCRIPT
- * DATABASES: MYSQL, POSTGRESQL
- * FRAMEWORKS: RUBY ON RAILS, REACT
- * METHODOLOGIES: AGILE, TDD

WORK HISTORY

FULL STACK DEVELOPER (MEOW STORES - NEDERLAND) – 2017-2018

Tech: React, MobX, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap/Bulma, Jest, Postgresql, Json Web Tokens, Sass, various API's (AWS S3, Stripe, Cloudinary)

- Team Lead implementing a modern e-commerce solution with a (Rails) web API and a performant React web UI. (Work in progress!)
- Team Lead implementing a sales analysis solution.

• Team Lead - converting customers into web customers (sales analysis and discount offers for web purchases) .

FULL STACK DEVELOPER (ACHIRAL.IO - ROMANIA) - 2016-2017.

 Worked on webapp that processes data (Excell) on the fly, saves it and returns useful business information computed on the backend server.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER (GLORIA JEANS ROMANIA) - 2013-2016

Tech: Ruby on Rails, Redis, Elastic Search, Jquery, HAML

- Software Developer on the team that implemented search and profitability analysis on products.
- Software Developer on the team that implemented sales analysis.
- Developed marketing promotion app to automatically find and reward the top 3 customers of the week.

BUSINESS ANALYST (ARABESQUE - GALATI, ROMANIA) – 2004-2008

- Gather information, evaluate business operations, determine business objectives
- Prepare technical reports and analyse trends
- Evaluate and interpret data for business analysis and strategic decision-making

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE - PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION - LEIDEN
UNIVERSITY - 2016 - NETHERLANDS

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE - PUBLIC MANAGEMENT - THE HAGUE
UNIVERSITY - 2013 - NETHERLANDS

REFERENCES

Florin Toader - CTO at Achiral software. <u>office@achiral.io</u>
Gianna Cipollone - Owner at Meow Stores Netherlands. info@meowstores.nl
Mihai Florescu - Manager at Gloria Jeans Romania. <u>mflorescu@gloriajeans.ro</u>